<productRequirementsDocument>
    <title>PRD for Ecommerce Platform</title>
    <executiveSummary>The Ecommerce Platform project aims to develop a modern, scalable, and competitive e-commerce solution targeting small to mid-market businesses. Built on a composable architecture with AI-powered personalization, mobile-first PWA capabilities, and omnichannel fulfillment options like BOPIS, this platform will compete with market leaders like Shopify and BigCommerce. The platform will achieve a 3% conversion rate within the first year, increase Average Order Value by 10% through AI recommendations, and capture 5% of the target SMB market within two years. Key success metrics include maintaining 99.9% uptime, sub-2-second page load times, and WCAG 2.1 AA compliance while ensuring full GDPR, CCPA, and PCI DSS regulatory compliance.</executiveSummary>

    <scope>
        <inScope>
            • AI-powered product discovery and personalized recommendations
            • Mobile-first Progressive Web App (PWA) architecture
            • Advanced search with autocomplete and filtering capabilities
            • Comprehensive product details pages with rich media and 360-degree views
            • One-page frictionless checkout with guest checkout support
            • Multiple payment methods (Credit Card, PayPal, Apple Pay, BNPL)
            • Omnichannel fulfillment with BOPIS (Buy Online, Pick-up In Store)
            • User account management with order history and tracking
            • Self-service return initiation system with RMA generation
            • GDPR/CCPA compliant data privacy controls
            • SEO-optimized product and category pages with schema.org markup
            • Real-time inventory management and availability display
        </inScope>
        <outOfScope>
            • Social commerce and live shopping features (planned for v2.0)
            • Advanced B2B features like bulk ordering and custom pricing
            • Multi-vendor marketplace capabilities
            • Native mobile applications (iOS/Android)
            • Advanced analytics and business intelligence dashboard
            • Subscription and recurring payment models
            • Cryptocurrency payment options
            • Voice commerce integration
            • Augmented reality product visualization
        </outOfScope>
        <dependencies>
            <externalServices>
                • Payment Service Provider (Stripe/PayPal) for PCI DSS compliant processing
                • Third-party logistics (3PL) API integration for shipping and fulfillment
                • CDN provider (Cloudflare/AWS CloudFront) for global content delivery
                • Email service provider (SendGrid/SES) for transactional emails
                • AI/ML service (AWS Personalize/Google Recommendations AI) for recommendations
                • Search service (Algolia/Elasticsearch) for advanced search capabilities
            </externalServices>
            <prerequisites>
                • Design system approval and component library
                • Security audit and penetration testing plan
                • Legal review for GDPR/CCPA compliance
                • PCI DSS compliance assessment
                • Product data migration strategy and tools
                • Third-party service contracts and SLAs
            </prerequisites>
        </dependencies>
        <assumptions>
            • Target customers are comfortable with online shopping and digital payments
            • Initial product data will be provided in structured format
            • Merchants will handle shipping or use integrated 3PL providers
            • AI personalization engine will have sufficient data for accurate recommendations
            • Mobile devices will account for >60% of traffic
            • Users expect Amazon-like checkout experience
            • SEO optimization will drive significant organic traffic
        </assumptions>
        <constraints>
            <technicalConstraints>
                • Must use headless/composable architecture
                • RESTful APIs required for third-party integrations
                • No storage of sensitive payment card data on-platform
                • Must support all major browsers (Chrome, Safari, Firefox, Edge)
                • Mobile-first responsive design required
            </technicalConstraints>
            <businessConstraints>
                • Fixed initial launch budget requiring MVP prioritization
                • Must achieve profitability within 24 months
                • Competitive pricing pressure from established platforms
                • Need to balance feature richness with ease of use
            </businessConstraints>
            <resourceConstraints>
                • Limited development team size for initial launch
                • Need for specialized skills in AI/ML and security
                • Dependency on third-party service availability and pricing
            </resourceConstraints>
        </constraints>
    </scope>

    <businessGoals>
        <primaryObjectives>
            • Achieve 3% conversion rate within 12 months through optimized user journey
            • Increase Average Order Value by 10% through AI-driven recommendations
            • Capture 5% of SMB to mid-market segment within 24 months
            • Support 100% year-over-year transaction volume growth for 3 years
            • Maintain cart abandonment rate below 60% with frictionless checkout
        </primaryObjectives>
        <keyPerformanceIndicators>
            <kpi name="conversion_rate" target="3%" timeframe="12 months" measurement="purchases / sessions">
                <description>Track conversion rate through analytics platform, segment by traffic source and device type</description>
            </kpi>
            <kpi name="aov_growth" target="10% increase" timeframe="12 months" measurement="average order value analytics">
                <description>Measure AOV before and after recommendation engine implementation</description>
            </kpi>
            <kpi name="market_share" target="5%" timeframe="24 months" measurement="industry reports and customer acquisition">
                <description>Track new merchant sign-ups against total addressable market</description>
            </kpi>
            <kpi name="cart_abandonment" target="<60%" timeframe="6 months" measurement="checkout funnel analytics">
                <description>Monitor abandonment at each checkout step, implement exit-intent surveys</description>
            </kpi>
            <kpi name="platform_uptime" target="99.9%" timeframe="continuous" measurement="system monitoring tools">
                <description>24/7 monitoring with automated alerts for downtime incidents</description>
            </kpi>
        </keyPerformanceIndicators>
        <successMetrics>
            <metric name="customer_satisfaction" target="4.5+ stars" measurement="CSAT surveys and reviews">
                <trackingMethod>Net Promoter Score (NPS > 40), Customer Satisfaction Score (CSAT > 4.5/5), quarterly surveys</trackingMethod>
            </metric>
            <metric name="performance_metrics" target="Page load < 2s" measurement="Google PageSpeed Insights">
                <description>95th percentile page load time under 2 seconds, Core Web Vitals in green zone</description>
            </metric>
        </successMetrics>
    </businessGoals>

    <nonFunctionalRequirements>
        <performance>
            <pageLoadTime target="&lt; 2 seconds" measurement="95th percentile">
                <description>Target page load times for all critical user journeys, especially PDP and checkout</description>
            </pageLoadTime>
            <apiResponse target="&lt; 500ms" measurement="99th percentile">
                <description>API response time requirements for product search, checkout, and user authentication</description>
            </apiResponse>
            <uptime target="99.9%" measurement="monthly availability">
                <description>System uptime and reliability targets with automated failover capabilities</description>
            </uptime>
            <concurrency target="1000 concurrent users" measurement="load testing">
                <description>Support for 1000+ concurrent users with auto-scaling infrastructure</description>
            </concurrency>
        </performance>
        <security>
            <authentication target="OAuth 2.0" measurement="SSO support">
                <description>Multi-factor authentication, social login options, secure session management</description>
            </authentication>
            <authorization target="Role-Based Access Control" measurement="RBAC implementation">
                <description>Admin, merchant, customer roles with granular permission controls</description>
            </authorization>
            <dataEncryption target="End-to-End" measurement="AES-256">
                <description>TLS 1.3 for all traffic, AES-256 encryption for data at rest, PII protection</description>
            </dataEncryption>
            <compliance target="GDPR, CCPA, SOC 2" measurement="third-party audit">
                <description>Annual SOC 2 Type II audit, GDPR data protection officer, CCPA compliance tools</description>
            </compliance>
        </security>
        <accessibility target="WCAG 2.1 AA" measurement="automated testing + manual review">
            <description>Keyboard navigation, screen reader support, color contrast compliance, focus management</description>
        </accessibility>
        <internationalization target="English (initial) + 5 more languages" measurement="localization testing">
            <description>Support for multiple currencies, date formats, and right-to-left languages in v2.0</description>
        </internationalization>
    </nonFunctionalRequirements>

    <useCases>
        <useCase id="UC-001" name="Discover and Search Products with AI-Powered Personalization" priority="High">
            <description>A user discovers products through browsing categories, using search with autocomplete, and receiving AI-driven personalized recommendations on homepage and category pages. Leverages mobile-first design and PWA capabilities for fast, app-like experience.</description>
            <primaryActor>Guest User, Registered Customer</primaryActor>
            <secondaryActors>AI Recommendation Engine, Search Service</secondaryActors>
            <preconditions>The e-commerce platform is online and accessible. Product catalog is populated and up-to-date. AI personalization engine is active.</preconditions>
            <mainFlow>
                <step number="1">The user accesses the platform's homepage via web browser or mobile device</step>
                <step number="2">The system displays personalized product selection based on browsing history and demographics</step>
                <step number="3">The user uses search bar with real-time autocomplete suggestions</step>
                <step number="4">Alternatively, user navigates through product categories and sub-categories</step>
                <step number="5">User applies filters (price, brand, size, color, rating) on category/search results</step>
                <step number="6">System dynamically updates product grid with SEO-friendly URLs</step>
                <step number="7">User views product list with image, name, price, and rating</step>
                <step number="8">User clicks on product to view detailed page</step>
            </mainFlow>
            <alternativeFlows>
                <flow id="A1">
                    <description>No Search Results</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step number="1">System displays 'No results found' message</step>
                        <step number="2">System offers alternative suggestions and popular categories</step>
                    </steps>
                </flow>
                <flow id="A2">
                    <description>Overly Specific Filters</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step number="1">System informs user of zero results</step>
                        <step number="2">System suggests removing filters to broaden search</step>
                    </steps>
                </flow>
            </alternativeFlows>
            <postconditions>User successfully navigates to product details page or refines discovery criteria</postconditions>
            <errorPaths>
                <path id="E1">
                    <description>Search service unavailable</description>
                    <resolution>Display cached results and error message, fallback to basic category browsing</resolution>
                </path>
            </errorPaths>
            <nonFunctionalRequirements>Page load time < 2s, WCAG 2.1 AA compliance, SEO optimization with schema.org markup</nonFunctionalRequirements>
        </useCase>
        <useCase id="UC-002" name="View Product Details and Evaluate Purchase Options" priority="High">
            <description>User views comprehensive product details page with high-quality media, social proof, real-time inventory, and omnichannel fulfillment options like BOPIS to evaluate purchase decision.</description>
            <primaryActor>Guest User, Registered Customer</primaryActor>
            <secondaryActors>Inventory Management System, Store Locator Service</secondaryActors>
            <preconditions>The user has navigated to a Product Details Page (PDP).</preconditions>
            <mainFlow>
                <step number="1">System displays optimized product page for fast loading on all devices</step>
                <step number="2">High-resolution images and 360-degree view or video are featured</step>
                <step number="3">System displays product information: name, price, SKU, description, reviews</step>
                <step number="4">Real-time inventory status is shown (In Stock, Only 3 left, Out of Stock)</step>
                <step number="5">BOPIS options displayed with nearby store availability and pickup time</step>
                <step number="6">User selects variants (size, color) with dynamic price and image updates</step>
                <step number="7">AI-powered cross-selling section displays related products</step>
                <step number="8">User clicks 'Add to Cart' button for desired variant</step>
            </mainFlow>
            <alternativeFlows>
                <flow id="A1">
                    <description>Product Out of Stock</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step number="1">'Add to Cart' button is disabled</step>
                        <step number="2">System offers 'Notify me when available' option</step>
                    </steps>
                </flow>
                <flow id="A2">
                    <description>BOPIS Unavailable</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step number="1">BOPIS option not displayed for user's location</step>
                        <step number="2">System shows only shipping options</step>
                    </steps>
                </flow>
            </alternativeFlows>
            <postconditions>Product added to cart or user has all information for purchase decision</postconditions>
            <errorPaths>
                <path id="E1">
                    <description>Inventory service unavailable</description>
                    <resolution>Display cached inventory data with disclaimer, disable checkout if critical</resolution>
                </path>
            </errorPaths>
            <nonFunctionalRequirements>Image optimization and lazy loading, real-time inventory sync, mobile-responsive design</nonFunctionalRequirements>
        </useCase>
        <useCase id="UC-003" name="Perform a Frictionless, One-Page Checkout" priority="High">
            <description>User proceeds through streamlined, secure checkout process designed to minimize cart abandonment. Supports guest checkout, multiple payment methods, transparent shipping costs, and one-click purchase for returning customers.</description>
            <primaryActor>Guest User, Registered Customer</primaryActor>
            <secondaryActors>Payment Gateway, Shipping Calculator, Tax Service</secondaryActors>
            <preconditions>User has at least one item in shopping cart and clicked 'Checkout' button.</preconditions>
            <mainFlow>
                <step number="1">System presents single-page checkout view to avoid page reloads</step>
                <step number="2">User chooses 'Checkout as Guest' or 'Sign In'</step>
                <step number="3">User enters or confirms shipping information (pre-populated for registered users)</step>
                <step number="4">System displays shipping methods with transparent costs and delivery timelines</step>
                <step number="5">User selects preferred shipping method</step>
                <step number="6">System presents payment options (Credit Card, PayPal, Apple Pay, BNPL)</step>
                <step number="7">Registered users see 'One-Click Buy' option with pre-filled details</step>
                <step number="8">User enters new payment info or selects saved method (HTTPS/TLS secured)</step>
                <step number="9">Final order summary displayed for confirmation</step>
                <step number="10">User clicks 'Place Order', system processes payment via PCI DSS compliant gateway</step>
            </mainFlow>
            <alternativeFlows>
                <flow id="A1">
                    <description>Payment Declined</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step number="1">System displays clear error message</step>
                        <step number="2">User prompted to try different payment method</step>
                    </steps>
                </flow>
                <flow id="A2">
                    <description>Applying Promo Code</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step number="1">User enters promo code on checkout page</step>
                        <step number="2">System validates code and updates order total</step>
                    </steps>
                </flow>
            </alternativeFlows>
            <postconditions>Order successfully created, payment authorized, user redirected to confirmation page</postconditions>
            <errorPaths>
                <path id="E1">
                    <description>Payment gateway timeout</description>
                    <resolution>Display retry option, save cart state, notify user of processing delay</resolution>
                </path>
            </errorPaths>
            <nonFunctionalRequirements>PCI DSS compliance, HTTPS/TLS encryption, form validation, auto-save progress</nonFunctionalRequirements>
        </useCase>
        <useCase id="UC-004" name="Manage User Account and Order History" priority="Medium">
            <description>Registered customer logs into account to manage personal information, view order history, track shipments, and manage privacy settings including GDPR/CCPA data portability and deletion requests.</description>
            <primaryActor>Registered Customer</primaryActor>
            <secondaryActors>Order Management System, Email Service</secondaryActors>
            <preconditions>User has registered account and is logged into platform.</preconditions>
            <mainFlow>
                <step number="1">User navigates to 'My Account' dashboard</step>
                <step number="2">User views recent orders summary and clicks 'Order History'</step>
                <step number="3">User selects past order to view details, items, purchase date, status</step>
                <step number="4">For shipped orders, user views real-time tracking information</step>
                <step number="5">User navigates to 'Profile Settings' to update name, email, password</step>
                <step number="6">User navigates to 'Address Book' to add, edit, delete addresses</step>
                <step number="7">User navigates to 'Privacy & Data' section</step>
                <step number="8">User clicks 'Request My Data' for GDPR/CCPA data download</step>
                <step number="9">User clicks 'Delete My Account' triggering confirmation flow</step>
                <step number="10">All pages comply with WCAG 2.1 accessibility standards</step>
            </mainFlow>
            <alternativeFlows>
                <flow id="A1">
                    <description>Forgot Password</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step number="1">User clicks 'Forgot Password' from login page</step>
                        <step number="2">User enters email address</step>
                        <step number="3">System sends password reset link to registered email</step>
                    </steps>
                </flow>
            </alternativeFlows>
            <postconditions>User account information updated or data request logged for processing</postconditions>
            <errorPaths>
                <path id="E1">
                    <description>Email delivery failure for password reset</description>
                    <resolution>Display alternative verification method, notify user of potential email issues</resolution>
                </path>
            </errorPaths>
            <nonFunctionalRequirements>GDPR/CCPA compliance, data encryption, secure authentication, audit logging</nonFunctionalRequirements>
        </useCase>
        <useCase id="UC-005" name="Initiate a Self-Service Product Return" priority="Medium">
            <description>Registered customer easily initiates return for purchased item through account portal. Process is self-service with clear instructions, printable return label, and adherence to consumer protection laws.</description>
            <primaryActor>Registered Customer</primaryActor>
            <secondaryActors>Return Management System, Shipping Label Service</secondaryActors>
            <preconditions>User has registered account and completed order within return eligibility window.</preconditions>
            <mainFlow>
                <step number="1">User navigates to 'My Account' > 'Order History'</step>
                <step number="2">User selects order containing items to return</step>
                <step number="3">System displays order details and 'Return Items' button for eligible orders</step>
                <step number="4">User clicks 'Return Items' and system displays return policy</step>
                <step number="5">User selects specific items from order to return</step>
                <step number="6">User selects return reason from predefined dropdown list</step>
                <step number="7">System confirms return eligibility and provides instructions</step>
                <step number="8">User submits return request</step>
                <step number="9">System generates RMA number and printable PDF return shipping label</step>
                <step number="10">Order status updated to 'Return Requested' in user's account</step>
            </mainFlow>
            <alternativeFlows>
                <flow id="A1">
                    <description>Item Not Eligible for Return</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step number="1">'Return Items' button disabled for ineligible items</step>
                        <step number="2">System displays explanation of ineligibility</step>
                    </steps>
                </flow>
            </alternativeFlows>
            <postconditions>Return request created, user has RMA and label to ship item back</postconditions>
            <errorPaths>
                <path id="E1">
                    <description>Shipping label generation failure</description>
                    <resolution>Display manual return instructions, notify support team for label generation</resolution>
                </path>
            </errorPaths>
            <nonFunctionalRequirements>PDF generation, email notifications, return policy compliance, audit trail</nonFunctionalRequirements>
        </useCase>
    </useCases>

    <riskAssessment>
        <risk level="High" likelihood="Medium" impact="High">
            <description>Poor user experience in checkout process leads to high cart abandonment</description>
            <mitigationStrategy>Implement streamlined one-page checkout with guest checkout and multiple payment options. Conduct continuous A/B testing to optimize flow. Monitor funnel analytics weekly.</mitigationStrategy>
            <owner>UX Lead</owner>
            <status>Open</status>
        </risk>
        <risk level="High" likelihood="Low" impact="High">
            <description>Security breach compromising customer data or payment information</description>
            <mitigationStrategy>Strict adherence to PCI DSS, use HTTPS/TLS for all data, quarterly security audits, annual penetration testing. Avoid storing sensitive card data on-platform.</mitigationStrategy>
            <owner>Security Engineer</owner>
            <status>In Progress</status>
        </risk>
        <risk level="Medium" likelihood="Medium" impact="Medium">
            <description>Platform performance does not meet user expectations, leading to lost sales</description>
            <mitigationStrategy>Adopt mobile-first PWA architecture, implement CDN, enforce strict performance budgets. Continuous monitoring with real-time alerts.</mitigationStrategy>
            <owner>Performance Engineer</owner>
            <status>Open</status>
        </risk>
        <risk level="Medium" likelihood="High" impact="Medium">
            <description>Failure to comply with evolving data privacy regulations (GDPR, CCPA)</description>
            <mitigationStrategy>Engage legal counsel for policy review. Build privacy-by-design principles. Implement easy-to-use data portability and deletion tools.</mitigationStrategy>
            <owner>Compliance Officer</owner>
            <status>In Progress</status>
        </risk>
        <risk level="Low" likelihood="Medium" impact="Low">
            <description>AI personalization engine ineffective, providing irrelevant recommendations</description>
            <mitigationStrategy>Start with proven collaborative filtering models. Continuously train with user behavior data. Allow manual curation and rules-based recommendations as fallback.</mitigationStrategy>
            <owner>ML Engineer</owner>
            <status>Open</status>
        </risk>
    </riskAssessment>

    <implementationNotes>
        <technicalStack>React (Next.js) for frontend, Node.js (Express) for backend APIs, PostgreSQL for primary database, Redis for caching, Elasticsearch for search, AWS for cloud infrastructure</technicalStack>
        <developmentApproach>Agile methodology with 2-week sprints, continuous integration/deployment, test-driven development, code reviews, and automated testing</developmentApproach>
        <testingStrategy>Unit testing (Jest), integration testing (Supertest), E2E testing (Cypress), performance testing (Lighthouse), security testing (OWASP ZAP), accessibility testing (axe-core)</testingStrategy>
        <deploymentStrategy>Containerized deployment with Docker/Kubernetes, blue-green deployments, CDN integration, auto-scaling configuration, multi-region deployment for redundancy</deploymentStrategy>
    </implementationNotes>
</productRequirementsDocument>