<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<use_cases>
  <use_cases>
    <item_0>
      <id>UC-001</id>
      <title>Mobile-First Product Browsing and Search</title>
      <description>Customers browse and search for products using a mobile-first interface with responsive design and AI-powered recommendations. The system provides fast loading times, robust filtering options, and personalized product suggestions based on user behavior and preferences.</description>
      <actors>
        <item_0>Customer</item_0>
        <item_1>Product Catalog System</item_1>
        <item_2>AI Recommendation Engine</item_2>
      </actors>
      <preconditions>
        <item_0>User has internet access</item_0>
        <item_1>Product catalog is populated</item_1>
        <item_2>User profile exists (optional)</item_2>
      </preconditions>
      <main_flow>
        <item_0>Customer accesses the e-commerce platform via mobile device</item_0>
        <item_1>System displays homepage optimized for mobile viewing</item_1>
        <item_2>Customer uses search bar or navigates through categories</item_2>
        <item_3>System returns relevant products with filtering options</item_3>
        <item_4>AI engine provides personalized recommendations</item_4>
        <item_5>Customer selects a product to view details</item_5>
      </main_flow>
      <alternate_flows>
        <item_0>Customer applies filters to refine search results</item_0>
        <item_1>Customer sorts products by price, rating, or popularity</item_1>
        <item_2>Customer views product recommendations without logging in</item_2>
      </alternate_flows>
      <postconditions>
        <item_0>Customer views product details or search results</item_0>
        <item_1>System logs browsing behavior for personalization</item_1>
      </postconditions>
      <priority>high</priority>
      <business_value>Addresses mobile-first commerce trend and improves user engagement through personalization, directly impacting conversion rates and customer satisfaction</business_value>
    </item_0>
    <item_1>
      <id>UC-002</id>
      <title>Guest Checkout with Multiple Payment Options</title>
      <description>Customers can complete purchases without creating an account using a streamlined checkout process that supports multiple secure payment gateways. The system ensures PCI DSS compliance and provides transparent pricing information.</description>
      <actors>
        <item_0>Customer</item_0>
        <item_1>Payment Gateway</item_1>
        <item_2>Order Management System</item_2>
      </actors>
      <preconditions>
        <item_0>Customer has added items to cart</item_0>
        <item_1>Payment gateways are configured and active</item_1>
        <item_2>Inventory is available for selected items</item_2>
      </preconditions>
      <main_flow>
        <item_0>Customer selects checkout option</item_0>
        <item_1>System presents guest checkout option</item_1>
        <item_2>Customer enters shipping information</item_2>
        <item_3>System displays transparent pricing including taxes and shipping</item_3>
        <item_4>Customer selects payment method</item_4>
        <item_5>Customer enters payment details</item_5>
        <item_6>System processes payment securely</item_6>
        <item_7>Order confirmation is generated and sent to customer</item_7>
      </main_flow>
      <alternate_flows>
        <item_0>Customer chooses to create account during checkout</item_0>
        <item_1>Payment fails and customer selects alternative payment method</item_1>
        <item_2>Customer modifies shipping address during checkout</item_2>
      </alternate_flows>
      <postconditions>
        <item_0>Order is created in the system</item_0>
        <item_1>Payment is processed or authorized</item_1>
        <item_2>Customer receives order confirmation</item_2>
      </postconditions>
      <priority>high</priority>
      <business_value>Reduces purchase friction and supports industry best practices for checkout experience, directly improving conversion rates and meeting competitor standards</business_value>
    </item_1>
    <item_2>
      <id>UC-003</id>
      <title>Omnichannel Order Tracking and Account Management</title>
      <description>Customers can track their orders across all channels and manage their account information through a unified interface. The system provides real-time inventory updates and seamless integration between online and offline experiences.</description>
      <actors>
        <item_0>Customer</item_0>
        <item_1>Order Management System</item_1>
        <item_2>Inventory System</item_2>
      </actors>
      <preconditions>
        <item_0>Customer has placed at least one order</item_0>
        <item_1>Order tracking system is integrated with logistics providers</item_1>
        <item_2>Customer account exists</item_2>
      </preconditions>
      <main_flow>
        <item_0>Customer logs into their account</item_0>
        <item_1>System displays order history and current order status</item_1>
        <item_2>Customer selects an order to view detailed tracking information</item_2>
        <item_3>System shows real-time delivery updates</item_3>
        <item_4>Customer can modify account information or preferences</item_4>
        <item_5>Customer can view saved payment methods and addresses</item_5>
      </main_flow>
      <alternate_flows>
        <item_0>Customer receives order status notifications via email/SMS</item_0>
        <item_1>Customer updates delivery preferences for active order</item_1>
        <item_2>Customer cancels order within allowed time window</item_2>
      </alternate_flows>
      <postconditions>
        <item_0>Customer has current order status information</item_0>
        <item_1>Account information is updated if modifications were made</item_1>
      </postconditions>
      <priority>high</priority>
      <business_value>Meets user expectations for omnichannel experience and order transparency, improving customer satisfaction and reducing support inquiries</business_value>
    </item_2>
    <item_3>
      <id>UC-004</id>
      <title>Product Reviews and Community Ratings</title>
      <description>Customers can view, submit, and manage product reviews and ratings. The system implements a comprehensive review system that builds trust and provides social proof, following competitor best practices from community-driven marketplaces.</description>
      <actors>
        <item_0>Customer</item_0>
        <item_1>Review Management System</item_1>
        <item_2>Product Catalog</item_2>
      </actors>
      <preconditions>
        <item_0>Customer has purchased or viewed a product</item_0>
        <item_1>Review system is configured and active</item_1>
        <item_2>Customer account exists</item_2>
      </preconditions>
      <main_flow>
        <item_0>Customer views product details page</item_0>
        <item_1>System displays existing reviews and average rating</item_1>
        <item_2>Customer selects to write a review</item_2>
        <item_3>Customer submits rating and written review</item_3>
        <item_4>System validates review authenticity</item_4>
        <item_5>Review is published after moderation (if required)</item_5>
        <item_6>Other customers can view the new review</item_6>
      </main_flow>
      <alternate_flows>
        <item_0>Customer reports inappropriate review</item_0>
        <item_1>Customer updates their existing review</item_1>
        <item_2>Customer finds reviews helpful and flags accordingly</item_2>
      </alternate_flows>
      <postconditions>
        <item_0>Product review is stored in system</item_0>
        <item_1>Product average rating is updated</item_1>
        <item_2>Review is visible to other customers (after moderation)</item_2>
      </postconditions>
      <priority>medium</priority>
      <business_value>Implements community-driven features that build trust and engagement, following successful models from leading competitors while providing valuable user-generated content</business_value>
    </item_3>
    <item_4>
      <id>UC-005</id>
      <title>Headless Commerce API Integration</title>
      <description>Third-party systems and frontend applications can interact with the e-commerce platform through RESTful APIs to retrieve product information, process orders, and manage inventory. This supports headless commerce architecture adoption trends.</description>
      <actors>
        <item_0>Third-Party Developer</item_0>
        <item_1>API Gateway</item_1>
        <item_2>Backend Services</item_2>
      </actors>
      <preconditions>
        <item_0>API credentials are provisioned</item_0>
        <item_1>Third-party application is registered</item_1>
        <item_2>Backend services are operational</item_2>
      </preconditions>
      <main_flow>
        <item_0>Third-party application authenticates with API gateway</item_0>
        <item_1>Application requests product catalog data</item_1>
        <item_2>API gateway validates credentials and routes request</item_2>
        <item_3>Backend services retrieve and format product data</item_3>
        <item_4>API returns structured product information</item_4>
        <item_5>Third-party application displays data in custom interface</item_5>
      </main_flow>
      <alternate_flows>
        <item_0>Authentication fails and appropriate error is returned</item_0>
        <item_1>Requested product is out of stock and inventory status is provided</item_1>
        <item_2>Rate limiting is enforced for high-volume requests</item_2>
      </alternate_flows>
      <postconditions>
        <item_0>Third-party application receives requested data</item_0>
        <item_1>API usage is logged for analytics and billing</item_1>
        <item_2>System maintains data consistency across channels</item_2>
      </postconditions>
      <priority>medium</priority>
      <business_value>Supports headless commerce architecture trend and enables flexible integration with various frontend experiences, positioning the platform for future scalability and omnichannel expansion</business_value>
    </item_4>
    <item_5>
      <id>UC-006</id>
      <title>Sustainability-Focused Shopping Experience</title>
      <description>Customers can identify and filter products based on sustainability criteria such as carbon footprint, eco-friendly materials, and ethical sourcing. The system provides transparent sustainability information aligned with growing consumer environmental consciousness.</description>
      <actors>
        <item_0>Customer</item_0>
        <item_1>Product Catalog System</item_1>
        <item_2>Sustainability Data Service</item_2>
      </actors>
      <preconditions>
        <item_0>Sustainability data is available for products</item_0>
        <item_1>Sustainability filters are configured</item_1>
        <item_2>Customer is browsing products</item_2>
      </preconditions>
      <main_flow>
        <item_0>Customer accesses product browsing interface</item_0>
        <item_1>System displays sustainability badges/filters</item_1>
        <item_2>Customer applies sustainability filters</item_2>
        <item_3>System returns products meeting sustainability criteria</item_3>
        <item_4>Customer views detailed sustainability information for product</item_4>
        <item_5>Customer makes purchase decision based on sustainability factors</item_5>
      </main_flow>
      <alternate_flows>
        <item_0>Customer compares sustainability metrics between products</item_0>
        <item_1>Customer views sustainability certifications and documentation</item_1>
        <item_2>Customer shares sustainability information on social platforms</item_2>
      </alternate_flows>
      <postconditions>
        <item_0>Customer views sustainability-focused product information</item_0>
        <item_1>System tracks sustainability-based browsing behavior</item_1>
        <item_2>Purchase decisions may be influenced by sustainability factors</item_2>
      </postconditions>
      <priority>medium</priority>
      <business_value>Addresses sustainability-focused shopping trend and differentiates the platform in the market while meeting evolving consumer expectations for transparent environmental impact information</business_value>
    </item_5>
  </use_cases>
  <business_requirements>
    <overview>E-commerce Platform v2 is a next-generation e-commerce solution designed to meet evolving industry standards and consumer expectations. The platform incorporates mobile-first design, AI-powered personalization, headless commerce architecture, and sustainability-focused features to compete with market leaders while ensuring regulatory compliance and optimal user experience.</overview>
    <business_goals>
      <item_0>Increase mobile conversion rates by 25% through mobile-first optimization</item_0>
      <item_1>Improve customer retention by 20% with personalized experiences</item_1>
      <item_2>Achieve 99.9% uptime and sub-2-second page load times</item_2>
      <item_3>Expand to 5000+ products with real-time inventory management</item_3>
      <item_4>Comply with all applicable data privacy and payment security regulations</item_4>
      <item_5>Enable seamless omnichannel shopping experience across all touchpoints</item_5>
    </business_goals>
    <success_criteria>
      <item_0>Mobile traffic conversion rate increase of 25% within 6 months</item_0>
      <item_1>Customer satisfaction score of 4.5+ out of 5.0</item_1>
      <item_2>API response time under 200ms for 95% of requests</item_2>
      <item_3>Zero security incidents or data breaches</item_3>
      <item_4>99.9% system availability during business hours</item_4>
      <item_5>50% increase in repeat purchases within 12 months</item_5>
    </success_criteria>
    <constraints>
      <item_0>Must comply with PCI DSS, GDPR, and CCPA regulations</item_0>
      <item_1>Platform must support 10,000 concurrent users</item_1>
      <item_2>Page load times must not exceed 2 seconds</item_2>
      <item_3>All interfaces must meet WCAG 2.1 AA accessibility standards</item_3>
      <item_4>Integration with existing ERP and inventory systems required</item_4>
      <item_5>Budget cap of $2M for initial development and deployment</item_5>
    </constraints>
    <assumptions>
      <item_0>Existing customer base will adopt new features with minimal training</item_0>
      <item_1>Third-party logistics providers will integrate with new tracking APIs</item_1>
      <item_2>Payment gateway providers will support required security standards</item_2>
      <item_3>Product suppliers will provide sustainability data as requested</item_3>
      <item_4>Development team will have access to necessary testing environments</item_4>
      <item_5>Marketing team will effectively communicate new features to users</item_5>
    </assumptions>
    <risks>
      <item_0>
        <risk>Security vulnerabilities could lead to data breaches</risk>
        <mitigation>Implement comprehensive security testing, regular audits, and real-time monitoring</mitigation>
      </item_0>
      <item_1>
        <risk>Performance issues during peak traffic periods</risk>
        <mitigation>Conduct load testing, implement auto-scaling, and use CDN for content delivery</mitigation>
      </item_1>
      <item_2>
        <risk>Integration challenges with legacy systems</risk>
        <mitigation>Develop comprehensive API layer and maintain detailed documentation</mitigation>
      </item_2>
      <item_3>
        <risk>Regulatory compliance failures</risk>
        <mitigation>Engage legal counsel early, implement compliance monitoring, and conduct regular audits</mitigation>
      </item_3>
      <item_4>
        <risk>User adoption of new features may be slow</risk>
        <mitigation>Implement user training programs, provide clear documentation, and gather user feedback</mitigation>
      </item_4>
    </risks>
  </business_requirements>
  <project_name>E-commerce Platform v2</project_name>
</use_cases>