<productRequirementsDocument>
    <title>PRD for Fitness Tracking App</title>
    <executiveSummary>The Fitness Tracking App project aims to develop a comprehensive mobile application that leverages AI, wearable integrations, and gamification to provide personalized fitness and wellness tracking. It incorporates industry trends like holistic wellness and data privacy, while differentiating through seamless ecosystems and ethical data practices, targeting market leaders like Fitbit and Strava. The app will enable users to register securely, track activities in real-time, receive AI-driven recommendations, engage socially, manage privacy, and integrate with third-party services, all while ensuring compliance with global regulations and achieving key business goals such as market share growth and user retention.</executiveSummary>
    <scope>
        <inScope>
            <item>User registration and authentication with OAuth 2.0 integration.</item>
            <item>Activity tracking and real-time feedback via wearable devices.</item>
            <item>Personalized workout and nutrition recommendations using AI.</item>
            <item>Social sharing and gamified challenges.</item>
            <item>Data privacy and settings management for compliance.</item>
            <item>Third-party integrations and ecosystem sync.</item>
        </inScope>
        <outOfScope>
            <item>Web-based platform or desktop application versions.</item>
            <item>Advanced medical diagnostics or integration with hospital systems.</item>
            <item>Offline multiplayer challenges or external payment gateways beyond app stores.</item>
            <item>Support for non-smartphone devices or legacy OS versions.</item>
        </outOfScope>
    </scope>
    <businessGoals>
        <goal>Achieve 20% market share in the fitness app segment within two years by offering superior personalization and integrations.</goal>
        <goal>Increase user retention by 30% through gamified features and real-time feedback.</goal>
        <goal>Ensure compliance with global regulations to build trust and avoid penalties.</goal>
        <goal>Foster a scalable platform for third-party partnerships and monetization via premium features.</goal>
    </businessGoals>
    <useCases>
        <useCaseModel>
            <useCase>
                <title>User Registration and Authentication</title>
                <primaryActor>New User</primaryActor>
                <secondaryActors>
                    <actor>Existing User</actor>
                </secondaryActors>
                <description>This use case allows new users to create an account and authenticate securely, incorporating OAuth 2.0 for third-party integrations and ensuring compliance with data privacy regulations like GDPR and CCPA. It aligns with best practices for robust data security and user-centric design.</description>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User launches the app and selects 'Sign Up' or 'Log In'.</step>
                    <step>For new users, user provides email, password, and consents to privacy policy and terms.</step>
                    <step>System validates input and creates account, sending verification email.</step>
                    <step>User verifies email and completes profile setup, including age and fitness goals.</step>
                    <step>For authentication, user enters credentials or uses OAuth via Google/Apple.</step>
                    <step>System authenticates user and grants access to dashboard.</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternativeFlows>
                    <flow id="A1" trigger="Email is already registered">
                        <step>System prompts for login instead.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A2" trigger="OAuth fails">
                        <step>Fallback to manual login.</step>
                    </flow>
                </alternativeFlows>
                <exceptionFlows>
                </exceptionFlows>
            </useCase>
            <useCase>
                <title>Activity Tracking and Real-Time Feedback</title>
                <primaryActor>User</primaryActor>
                <secondaryActors>
                    <actor>Wearable Device</actor>
                </secondaryActors>
                <description>Users can track physical activities such as steps, heart rate, and workouts with wearable integration via HealthKit or Google Fit APIs. Incorporates AI for personalized insights and real-time progress visualization, addressing user expectations for accuracy and minimal battery drain.</description>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User starts an activity (e.g., run) via app or wearable.</step>
                    <step>App syncs data in real-time from wearable using IoT ecosystems.</step>
                    <step>System tracks metrics like steps, heart rate, and calories burned.</step>
                    <step>App provides real-time feedback, such as pace alerts or hydration reminders.</step>
                    <step>User ends activity, and system saves data with AI-generated summary insights.</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternativeFlows>
                    <flow id="A1" trigger="Wearable is unavailable">
                        <step>Manual input option is provided.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A2" trigger="Data sync fails">
                        <step>Offline storage and later sync upon connection.</step>
                    </flow>
                </alternativeFlows>
                <exceptionFlows>
                </exceptionFlows>
            </useCase>
            <useCase>
                <title>Personalized Workout and Nutrition Recommendations</title>
                <primaryActor>User</primaryActor>
                <secondaryActors>
                    <actor>AI Engine</actor>
                </secondaryActors>
                <description>Leveraging AI and machine learning, the app provides tailored workout plans and nutrition advice based on user goals and data. Includes holistic wellness by integrating mental health prompts, aligning with industry trends and competitor strengths like MyFitnessPal.</description>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User accesses recommendations section.</step>
                    <step>AI analyzes user data (activities, nutrition logs, mental health entries).</step>
                    <step>System generates personalized workout plan and meal suggestions.</step>
                    <step>User receives notifications for daily tasks, including mental health check-ins.</step>
                    <step>User can customize or accept recommendations.</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternativeFlows>
                    <flow id="A1" trigger="Insufficient data">
                        <step>System prompts for more input before generating recommendations.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A2" trigger="AI processing fails">
                        <step>Fallback to generic plans.</step>
                    </flow>
                </alternativeFlows>
                <exceptionFlows>
                </exceptionFlows>
            </useCase>
            <useCase>
                <title>Social Sharing and Gamified Challenges</title>
                <primaryActor>User</primaryActor>
                <secondaryActors>
                    <actor>Other Users</actor>
                </secondaryActors>
                <description>Users can share achievements, join challenges, and compete socially, incorporating gamification elements like rewards and leaderboards. This fosters motivation and community, inspired by Strava's social features and industry trends in engagement.</description>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User selects share option for an activity or achievement.</step>
                    <step>System posts to social feed with privacy controls.</step>
                    <step>User browses and joins challenges (e.g., step count goals).</step>
                    <step>App tracks progress and awards badges or points.</step>
                    <step>Leaderboards update in real-time via cloud synchronization.</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternativeFlows>
                    <flow id="A1" trigger="User opts out of sharing">
                        <step>Data remains private.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A2" trigger="Group challenges">
                        <step>Allow inviting friends via app.</step>
                    </flow>
                </alternativeFlows>
                <exceptionFlows>
                </exceptionFlows>
            </useCase>
            <useCase>
                <title>Data Privacy and Settings Management</title>
                <primaryActor>User</primaryActor>
                <secondaryActors>
                    <actor>System Administrator</actor>
                </secondaryActors>
                <description>Users manage their data privacy, including consent, data portability, and deletion, ensuring compliance with GDPR, CCPA, and HIPAA. Incorporates transparent policies and encryption, addressing rising regulatory focus and user expectations for trust.</description>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User accesses privacy settings in the app.</step>
                    <step>System displays current consents and data usage policies.</step>
                    <step>User updates preferences, such as opting out of data sharing.</step>
                    <step>For requests, system processes data export or deletion.</step>
                    <step>System confirms changes and logs for audit compliance.</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternativeFlows>
                    <flow id="A1" trigger="User under 13">
                        <step>COPPA restrictions apply, limiting features.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A2" trigger="High-risk changes">
                        <step>Admin reviews for security audits.</step>
                    </flow>
                </alternativeFlows>
                <exceptionFlows>
                </exceptionFlows>
            </useCase>
            <useCase>
                <title>Third-Party Integrations and Ecosystem Sync</title>
                <primaryActor>User</primaryActor>
                <secondaryActors>
                    <actor>Third-Party Service</actor>
                </secondaryActors>
                <description>The app integrates with external apps and devices via open APIs, enabling seamless data aggregation like Apple Health. This supports a unified experience, leveraging technical standards and competitor insights from Google Fit.</description>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User selects integration options in settings.</step>
                    <step>App connects via RESTful APIs (e.g., Google Fit).</step>
                    <step>Data from third-party sources syncs automatically.</step>
                    <step>System aggregates and displays unified health dashboard.</step>
                    <step>User receives cross-app insights and notifications.</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternativeFlows>
                    <flow id="A1" trigger="API fails">
                        <step>Manual sync option provided.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A2" trigger="Integrations disabled">
                        <step>Fallback to app-only mode.</step>
                    </flow>
                </alternativeFlows>
                <exceptionFlows>
                </exceptionFlows>
            </useCase>
        </useCaseModel>
    </useCases>
    <nonFunctionalRequirements>
        <requirement type="Security">All sensitive data must be encrypted at rest and in transit using AES-256, with compliance to GDPR, HIPAA, CCPA, and regular security audits to prevent breaches.</requirement>
        <requirement type="Performance">The system must provide real-time feedback and sync data within 2 seconds for 95% of operations, ensuring minimal battery drain and handling peak loads via scalable cloud architecture.</requirement>
    </nonFunctionalRequirements>
</productRequirementsDocument>