<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<use_cases>
  <use_cases>
    <item_0>
      <id>UC-001</id>
      <title>Discover and Search Products with AI-Powered Personalization</title>
      <description>A user, whether a guest or a registered customer, can discover products through browsing categories, using the search function with autocomplete, and receiving AI-driven personalized recommendations on the homepage and category pages. This use case leverages mobile-first design and PWA capabilities for a fast, app-like experience.</description>
      <actors>
        <item_0>Guest User</item_0>
        <item_1>Registered Customer</item_1>
      </actors>
      <preconditions>
        <item_0>The e-commerce platform is online and accessible.</item_0>
        <item_1>Product catalog is populated and up-to-date.</item_1>
        <item_2>AI personalization engine is active.</item_2>
      </preconditions>
      <main_flow>
        <item_0>The user accesses the platform's homepage via a web browser or mobile device.</item_0>
        <item_1>The system, leveraging AI, displays a personalized selection of products, 'Trending for You', and 'Recommended' sections based on browsing history, demographics, or popular items.</item_1>
        <item_2>The user uses the search bar, which provides real-time autocomplete suggestions based on product names, categories, and attributes.</item_2>
        <item_3>Alternatively, the user navigates through product categories and sub-categories.</item_3>
        <item_4>On a category or search results page, the user applies filters such as price, brand, size, color, and rating.</item_4>
        <item_5>The system dynamically updates the product grid to reflect the selected filters, with URLs adhering to SEO best practices (e.g., schema.org structured data).</item_5>
        <item_6>The user views the list of products, each displaying key information like image, name, price, and rating.</item_6>
        <item_7>The user clicks on a product to view its detailed page.</item_7>
      </main_flow>
      <alternate_flows>
        <item_0>
          <name>No Search Results</name>
          <steps>
            <item_0>If a search query yields no results, the system displays a 'No results found' message.</item_0>
            <item_1>The system offers alternative suggestions, such as corrected spelling, similar products, or popular categories.</item_1>
          </steps>
        </item_0>
        <item_1>
          <name>Overly Specific Filters</name>
          <steps>
            <item_0>If applied filters result in zero products, the system informs the user.</item_0>
            <item_1>The system suggests removing one or more filters to broaden the search.</item_1>
          </steps>
        </item_1>
      </alternate_flows>
      <postconditions>The user successfully navigates to a product details page or refines their product discovery criteria.</postconditions>
      <priority>high</priority>
      <business_value>Drives user engagement and increases conversion rates by making product discovery intuitive, fast, and highly relevant. AI personalization, a key industry trend, directly increases Average Order Value (AOV) and customer loyalty by mimicking best-in-class competitors.</business_value>
    </item_0>
    <item_1>
      <id>UC-002</id>
      <title>View Product Details and Evaluate Purchase Options</title>
      <description>A user views a comprehensive product details page (PDP) to evaluate a purchase. The PDP includes high-quality media, social proof, real-time inventory, and omnichannel fulfillment options like Buy Online, Pick-up In Store (BOPIS), aligning with modern user expectations and industry best practices.</description>
      <actors>
        <item_0>Guest User</item_0>
        <item_1>Registered Customer</item_1>
      </actors>
      <preconditions>
        <item_0>The user has navigated to a Product Details Page (PDP).</item_0>
      </preconditions>
      <main_flow>
        <item_0>The system displays the product page, optimized for fast loading on all devices (mobile-first).</item_0>
        <item_1>High-resolution product images and a 360-degree view or product video are prominently featured.</item_1>
        <item_2>The system displays key product information: name, price, SKU, detailed description, and customer reviews/ratings.</item_2>
        <item_3>Real-time inventory status is shown (e.g., 'In Stock', 'Only 3 left', 'Out of Stock').</item_3>
        <item_4>If applicable, BOPIS options are displayed, showing nearby store availability and estimated pickup time.</item_4>
        <item_5>The user can select product variants (e.g., size, color). The page updates dynamically with the corresponding price and image.</item_5>
        <item_6>An AI-powered 'Customers also bought' or 'You might also like' section is displayed to encourage cross-selling.</item_6>
        <item_7>The user clicks the 'Add to Cart' button for their desired variant.</item_7>
      </main_flow>
      <alternate_flows>
        <item_0>
          <name>Product Out of Stock</name>
          <steps>
            <item_0>If the selected product variant is out of stock, the 'Add to Cart' button is disabled.</item_0>
            <item_1>The system offers an option to 'Notify me when available', prompting the user to enter their email address.</item_1>
          </steps>
        </item_0>
        <item_1>
          <name>BOPIS Unavailable</name>
          <steps>
            <item_0>If BOPIS is not available for the user's location or the product, the option is not displayed.</item_0>
            <item_1>The system clearly shows only shipping options.</item_1>
          </steps>
        </item_1>
      </alternate_flows>
      <postconditions>The product is successfully added to the user's shopping cart, or the user has all necessary information to make a purchase decision.</postconditions>
      <priority>high</priority>
      <business_value>Provides critical information to build customer trust and reduce purchase hesitation. Features like BOPIS and rich media are competitive differentiators that directly impact conversion rates and meet modern consumer expectations for omnichannel flexibility.</business_value>
    </item_1>
    <item_2>
      <id>UC-003</id>
      <title>Perform a Frictionless, One-Page Checkout</title>
      <description>A user proceeds through a streamlined, secure checkout process designed to minimize cart abandonment. The process supports guest checkout, multiple payment methods, transparent shipping costs, and a one-click purchase option for returning customers, adhering to PCI DSS standards.</description>
      <actors>
        <item_0>Guest User</item_0>
        <item_1>Registered Customer</item_1>
      </actors>
      <preconditions>
        <item_0>The user has at least one item in their shopping cart.</item_0>
        <item_1>The user has clicked the 'Checkout' button.</item_1>
      </preconditions>
      <main_flow>
        <item_0>The system presents a single-page or accordion-style checkout view to avoid page reloads.</item_0>
        <item_1>The user is offered the choice to 'Checkout as Guest' or 'Sign In'.</item_1>
        <item_2>The user enters or confirms their shipping information. For registered customers, this information is pre-populated.</item_2>
        <item_3>The system displays available shipping methods (e.g., Standard, Express, BOPIS) with clear, transparent costs and estimated delivery timelines.</item_3>
        <item_4>The user selects their preferred shipping method.</item_4>
        <item_5>The system presents multiple payment options (e.g., Credit Card, PayPal, Apple Pay, 'Buy Now, Pay Later' services).</item_5>
        <item_6>For registered customers with saved payment methods, a 'One-Click Buy' option is available, pre-filling all details.</item_6>
        <item_7>The user enters new payment information or selects a saved method. All data transmission is secured with HTTPS/TLS.</item_7>
        <item_8>A final order summary, including items, subtotal, shipping, taxes, and total, is displayed for confirmation.</item_8>
        <item_9>The user clicks the 'Place Order' button. The system processes the payment via a PCI DSS compliant gateway.</item_9>
      </main_flow>
      <alternate_flows>
        <item_0>
          <name>Payment Declined</name>
          <steps>
            <item_0>If the payment is declined, the system displays a clear, non-technical error message.</item_0>
            <item_1>The user is prompted to try a different payment method or correct their information.</item_1>
          </steps>
        </item_0>
        <item_1>
          <name>Applying a Promo Code</name>
          <steps>
            <item_0>The user enters a promo code on the checkout page.</item_0>
            <item_1>The system validates the code and instantly updates the order total to reflect the discount.</item_1>
          </steps>
        </item_1>
      </alternate_flows>
      <postconditions>The order is successfully created, payment is authorized, and the user is redirected to an order confirmation page. An order confirmation email is sent.</postconditions>
      <priority>high</priority>
      <business_value>This is the most critical use case for revenue generation. A frictionless checkout, inspired by market leaders like Amazon, directly reduces cart abandonment rates, improves customer satisfaction, and increases conversion. Supporting diverse payment options caters to a broader audience.</business_value>
    </item_2>
    <item_3>
      <id>UC-004</id>
      <title>Manage User Account and Order History</title>
      <description>A registered customer logs into their account to manage personal information, view order history, track shipments, and manage privacy settings. This use case includes functionalities for data portability and deletion requests to ensure compliance with GDPR and CCPA.</description>
      <actors>
        <item_0>Registered Customer</item_0>
      </actors>
      <preconditions>
        <item_0>The user has a registered account.</item_0>
        <item_1>The user is logged into the platform.</item_1>
      </preconditions>
      <main_flow>
        <item_0>The user navigates to the 'My Account' dashboard.</item_0>
        <item_1>The user views a summary of recent orders and can click to view the full 'Order History'.</item_1>
        <item_2>Within Order History, the user can select a past order to see its details, including items, purchase date, and status.</item_2>
        <item_3>For shipped orders, the user can view real-time tracking information.</item_3>
        <item_4>The user navigates to the 'Profile Settings' section to update their name, email, or password.</item_4>
        <item_5>The user navigates to the 'Address Book' to add, edit, or delete shipping addresses.</item_5>
        <item_6>The user navigates to the 'Privacy &amp; Data' section.</item_6>
        <item_7>The user can click a 'Request My Data' button to initiate a GDPR/CCPA data download request.</item_7>
        <item_8>The user can click a 'Delete My Account' button, which triggers a confirmation flow to permanently delete their data.</item_8>
        <item_9>All pages are compliant with WCAG 2.1 accessibility standards.</item_9>
      </main_flow>
      <alternate_flows>
        <item_0>
          <name>Forgot Password</name>
          <steps>
            <item_0>From the login page, the user clicks 'Forgot Password'.</item_0>
            <item_1>The user enters their email address.</item_1>
            <item_2>The system sends a password reset link to the registered email.</item_2>
          </steps>
        </item_0>
      </alternate_flows>
      <postconditions>The user's account information, addresses, or privacy settings are successfully updated. A data request is logged for processing.</postconditions>
      <priority>medium</priority>
      <business_value>Enhances customer retention by providing a self-service portal for common tasks. Builds trust and ensures legal compliance with global privacy regulations like GDPR and CCPA, mitigating legal and reputational risks.</business_value>
    </item_3>
    <item_4>
      <id>UC-005</id>
      <title>Initiate a Self-Service Product Return</title>
      <description>A registered customer can easily initiate a return for a purchased item through their account portal. The process is self-service, providing clear instructions, a printable return shipping label, and adherence to consumer protection laws regarding returns.</description>
      <actors>
        <item_0>Registered Customer</item_0>
      </actors>
      <preconditions>
        <item_0>The user has a registered account.</item_0>
        <item_1>The user has at least one completed order that is within the return eligibility window.</item_1>
      </preconditions>
      <main_flow>
        <item_0>The user navigates to 'My Account' &gt; 'Order History'.</item_0>
        <item_1>The user selects the order containing the item(s) they wish to return.</item_1>
        <item_2>The system displays the order details and a 'Return Items' button, which is only active for eligible orders.</item_2>
        <item_3>The user clicks 'Return Items' and is presented with the return policy for clarity and compliance.</item_3>
        <item_4>The user selects the specific item(s) from the order they want to return.</item_4>
        <item_5>For each item, the user selects a reason for the return from a predefined dropdown list (e.g., 'Wrong Size', 'Damaged', 'No Longer Needed').</item_5>
        <item_6>The system confirms the return eligibility and provides instructions.</item_6>
        <item_7>The user submits the return request.</item_7>
        <item_8>The system generates a Return Merchandise Authorization (RMA) number and a printable PDF return shipping label.</item_8>
        <item_9>The order status in the user's account is updated to 'Return Requested'.</item_9>
      </main_flow>
      <alternate_flows>
        <item_0>
          <name>Item Not Eligible for Return</name>
          <steps>
            <item_0>If a user tries to return an item outside the eligibility window (e.g., final sale, past 30 days), the 'Return Items' button is disabled or a message explains why the item is not returnable.</item_0>
          </steps>
        </item_0>
      </alternate_flows>
      <postconditions>A return request is successfully created in the system, and the user has the necessary information (RMA, label) to ship the item back.</postconditions>
      <priority>medium</priority>
      <business_value>A simple and transparent return process is a key factor for customer trust and repeat business, as identified in user expectations. Automating this process reduces the load on customer support and ensures compliance with consumer protection regulations.</business_value>
    </item_4>
  </use_cases>
  <business_requirements>
    <overview>The 'Ecommerce Platform' project aims to develop a modern, scalable, and competitive e-commerce solution targeting small to mid-market businesses. The platform will be built on a composable architecture to allow for flexibility and future growth. It will incorporate industry-leading features such as AI-powered personalization, mobile-first Progressive Web App (PWA) experiences, and omnichannel fulfillment options like BOPIS. The platform will compete with market leaders like Shopify and BigCommerce by offering a balance of ease-of-use, powerful built-in features, and enterprise-grade capabilities, all while adhering to the highest technical and regulatory standards.</overview>
    <business_goals>
      <item_0>Achieve a 3% conversion rate within the first year of launch by optimizing the user journey and checkout process.</item_0>
      <item_1>Increase Average Order Value (AOV) by 10% through AI-driven product recommendations and cross-selling features.</item_1>
      <item_2>Capture 5% of the target SMB to mid-market segment within two years by offering a competitive feature set and flexible pricing.</item_2>
      <item_3>Ensure platform scalability to support a 100% year-over-year growth in transaction volume for the first three years.</item_3>
      <item_4>Maintain a cart abandonment rate below 60% by implementing a frictionless, one-page checkout experience.</item_4>
    </business_goals>
    <success_criteria>
      <item_0>Conversion Rate: Measured as (Purchases / Sessions) &gt; 3%.</item_0>
      <item_1>Cart Abandonment Rate: Measured as (Carts with 1+ items / Initiated Checkouts) &lt; 60%.</item_1>
      <item_2>Page Load Speed: Average page load time under 2 seconds, as measured by Google PageSpeed Insights.</item_2>
      <item_3>Accessibility Compliance: Achieve WCAG 2.1 AA level compliance across the platform.</item_3>
      <item_4>Uptime: Maintain 99.9% platform availability.</item_4>
      <item_5>AOV Growth: Demonstrate a 10% increase in AOV attributed to the recommendation engine.</item_5>
    </success_criteria>
    <constraints>
      <item_0>The platform must be fully compliant with PCI DSS for handling payment card information.</item_0>
      <item_1>All development must adhere to GDPR for EU users and CCPA for California residents.</item_1>
      <item_2>The solution must be built on a headless/composable architecture to support future integrations.</item_2>
      <item_3>The initial launch budget is fixed, requiring prioritization of high-impact features (MVP-first approach).</item_3>
      <item_4>The platform must support RESTful APIs for third-party integrations (e.g., ERP, CRM).</item_4>
    </constraints>
    <assumptions>
      <item_0>A reliable third-party Payment Service Provider (PSP) will be integrated for payment processing.</item_0>
      <item_1>Initial product data, including images and descriptions, will be provided by the client in a structured format.</item_1>
      <item_2>The target customer base is comfortable with online shopping and digital payment methods.</item_2>
      <item_3>Shipping and fulfillment will be handled either by the merchant or a third-party logistics (3PL) provider, with the platform integrating their APIs.</item_3>
    </assumptions>
    <risks>
      <item_0>
        <risk>Poor user experience in the checkout process leads to high cart abandonment.</risk>
        <mitigation>Implement a streamlined, one-page checkout with guest checkout and multiple payment options. Conduct continuous A/B testing to optimize the flow.</mitigation>
      </item_0>
      <item_1>
        <risk>Platform performance does not meet user expectations, leading to lost sales.</risk>
        <mitigation>Adopt a mobile-first PWA architecture, implement a CDN, and enforce strict performance budgets during development. Continuous performance monitoring is required.</mitigation>
      </item_1>
      <item_2>
        <risk>Security breach compromising customer data or payment information.</risk>
        <mitigation>Strict adherence to PCI DSS, use of HTTPS/TLS for all data, regular security audits, and penetration testing. Avoid storing sensitive card data on-platform.</mitigation>
      </item_2>
      <item_3>
        <risk>Failure to comply with evolving data privacy regulations (GDPR, CCPA).</risk>
        <mitigation>Engage legal counsel to review policies and processes. Build privacy-by-design principles into the platform, including easy-to-use data portability and deletion tools.</mitigation>
      </item_3>
      <item_4>
        <risk>The platform's personalization engine is ineffective, providing irrelevant recommendations.</risk>
        <mitigation>Start with proven collaborative filtering models and continuously train the AI with user behavior data. Allow for manual curation and rules-based recommendations as a fallback.</mitigation>
      </item_4>
    </risks>
  </business_requirements>
  <project_name>Ecommerce Platform</project_name>
</use_cases>