<productRequirementsDocument>
    <title>PRD for Fitness api updated</title>
    <executiveSummary>This project aims to develop a beginner-friendly fitness mobile application targeting users aged 25-45 who feel intimidated by existing fitness apps. The MVP will focus on simplified workout tracking with pre-made plans, AI-powered nutrition logging via photos, and private progress sharing. The app will be built on a React Native and Node.js stack, leveraging a freemium business model to drive user acquisition and monetization.</executiveSummary>
    <scope>
        <inScope>
            <item>Beginner-friendly and simple user interface.</item>
            <item>Workout logging functionality (exercises, reps, sets).</item>
            <item>Pre-made workout plans for beginners.</item>
            <item>Exercise demonstrations using images/GIFs or linked videos.</item>
            <item>Meal photo tracking with AI analysis.</item>
            <item>Progress visualization and tracking (e.g., photos, weight).</item>
            <item>Basic private social sharing features with trusted friends.</item>
            <item>Customizable push notifications and reminders.</item>
            <item>Integration with Apple Health and Google Fit.</item>
            <item>Freemium subscription model.</item>
        </inScope>
        <outOfScope>
            <item>Hosting video content directly; using external links for MVP.</item>
            <item>Public social features, community forums, or leaderboards.</item>
            <item>Manual calorie counting and detailed micronutrient tracking.</item>
            <item>Integrations beyond Apple Health and Google Fit (e.g., Strava, Garmin).</item>
            <item>Web version of the application.</item>
            <item>Live personal training or coaching features.</item>
        </outOfScope>
    </scope>
    <businessGoals>
        <goal>Acquire 50,000 active users within the first 6 months post-launch.</goal>
        <goal>Maintain a 30-day user retention rate of 40%.</goal>
    </businessGoals>
    <useCases>
        <useCaseModel>
            <useCase>
                <title>Beginner Onboarding and Personalized Profile Setup</title>
                <primaryActor>New User (Fitness Beginner)</primaryActor>
                <secondaryActors/>
                <description>New users complete a simplified onboarding process that creates a personalized fitness profile without overwhelming them with complex options, following the trend of simplified user experiences for fitness beginners.</description>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User opens the app and sees a welcoming, non-intimidating splash screen</step>
                    <step>User completes a brief fitness assessment (current activity level, goals, available equipment)</step>
                    <step>User selects primary fitness goals from beginner-friendly options (e.g., 'Build basic strength', 'Improve cardiovascular health')</step>
                    <step>User grants permissions for Apple Health/Google Fit integration</step>
                    <step>User sets up basic notification preferences</step>
                    <step>System creates a personalized dashboard with recommended starting plan</step>
                    <step>User is guided through a quick tutorial of core features</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternativeFlows>
                    <flow id="A1" trigger="User skips fitness assessment">
                        <step>System uses default beginner settings to create the profile.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A2" trigger="User declines health app integration">
                        <step>System proceeds with onboarding, and the user can enable integration later in settings.</step>
                    </flow>
                </alternativeFlows>
                <exceptionFlows/>
            </useCase>
            <useCase>
                <title>Workout Plan Selection and Guided Execution</title>
                <primaryActor>User (Fitness Beginner)</primaryActor>
                <secondaryActors/>
                <description>Users browse and select from curated beginner workout plans, then follow guided sessions with exercise demonstrations using images/GIFs to avoid video hosting costs while maintaining quality instruction.</description>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User navigates to the 'Workout Plans' section</step>
                    <step>System displays filtered recommendations based on user's goals and equipment</step>
                    <step>User browses plans with clear difficulty indicators and time commitments</step>
                    <step>User selects a plan and views detailed overview including exercises and schedule</step>
                    <step>User starts a workout session</step>
                    <step>System displays current exercise with image/GIF demonstration and simple instructions</step>
                    <step>User logs sets, reps, or duration for each exercise</step>
                    <step>System provides encouragement and form tips between exercises</step>
                    <step>User completes workout and receives summary and achievement notification</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternativeFlows>
                    <flow id="A1" trigger="User wants a custom workout">
                        <step>User creates a custom workout by selecting individual exercises from the library.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A2" trigger="User wants to modify a plan">
                        <step>User modifies an existing plan by swapping exercises for alternatives.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A3" trigger="User needs to pause">
                        <step>User pauses workout and the system saves progress for resuming later.</step>
                    </flow>
                </alternativeFlows>
                <exceptionFlows/>
            </useCase>
            <useCase>
                <title>AI-Powered Nutrition Tracking via Photo Capture</title>
                <primaryActor>User (Fitness Beginner)</primaryActor>
                <secondaryActors/>
                <description>Users capture photos of meals which are analyzed by third-party AI API to estimate nutritional content, providing a low-friction alternative to manual calorie counting that addresses the saturated nutrition tracking market.</description>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User taps 'Log Meal' button on nutrition dashboard</step>
                    <step>User selects 'Take Photo' option</step>
                    <step>User captures photo of their meal</step>
                    <step>System uploads photo to third-party AI service (e.g., Google Cloud Vision API)</step>
                    <step>AI returns estimated food items and nutritional information</step>
                    <step>User reviews and confirms or adjusts the AI analysis</step>
                    <step>User can add portion size if needed</step>
                    <step>System logs meal to daily nutrition summary</step>
                    <step>User sees updated daily nutrition dashboard with visual indicators</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternativeFlows>
                    <flow id="A1" trigger="AI fails to identify food">
                        <step>AI fails to identify food items and user manually enters the meal details.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A2" trigger="User prefers an existing photo">
                        <step>User uploads a photo from their gallery instead of taking a new one.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A3" trigger="User cancels logging">
                        <step>User skips logging and can return to the nutrition dashboard to log later.</step>
                    </flow>
                </alternativeFlows>
                <exceptionFlows/>
            </useCase>
            <useCase>
                <title>Progress Visualization and Goal Achievement</title>
                <primaryActor>User (Fitness Beginner)</primaryActor>
                <secondaryActors/>
                <description>Users view comprehensive progress dashboards showing workout consistency, strength improvements, and body composition changes through simple, motivating visualizations that celebrate small wins.</description>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User navigates to 'Progress' section</step>
                    <step>System displays dashboard with multiple progress widgets</step>
                    <step>User views workout consistency calendar showing completed sessions</step>
                    <step>User taps on strength widget to see progression on key exercises</step>
                    <step>User views body measurement trends (weight, photos if uploaded)</step>
                    <step>System celebrates milestones and achievements with badges</step>
                    <step>User can adjust goals based on current progress</step>
                    <step>System provides personalized insights and recommendations</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternativeFlows>
                    <flow id="A1" trigger="User wants to share data">
                        <step>User exports progress data for sharing with a trainer or personal records.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A2" trigger="User wants to compare periods">
                        <step>User compares current progress to previous time periods.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A3" trigger="User wants custom tracking">
                        <step>User adds custom measurements to track beyond the defaults.</step>
                    </flow>
                </alternativeFlows>
                <exceptionFlows/>
            </useCase>
            <useCase>
                <title>Private Progress Sharing with Trusted Friends</title>
                <primaryActor>User (Fitness Beginner)</primaryActor>
                <secondaryActors>
                    <actor>Trusted Friends</actor>
                </secondaryActors>
                <description>Users selectively share their progress and achievements with a small, trusted group of friends, providing social motivation without the complexity and moderation overhead of public social features.</description>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User navigates to 'Sharing' section</step>
                    <step>User selects 'Share Progress' option</step>
                    <step>User chooses specific achievements or milestones to share</step>
                    <step>User selects which friends to share with from their trusted list</step>
                    <step>User adds optional message of encouragement</step>
                    <step>System sends notification to selected friends</step>
                    <step>Friends can view shared progress and send reactions/encouragement</step>
                    <step>User receives notifications of friend responses</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternativeFlows>
                    <flow id="A1" trigger="User declines to share">
                        <step>User declines to share and keeps progress private.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A2" trigger="User wants to manage preferences">
                        <step>User adjusts sharing preferences for future automatic sharing.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A3" trigger="User wants to modify friend list">
                        <step>User removes friends from their sharing list.</step>
                    </flow>
                </alternativeFlows>
                <exceptionFlows/>
            </useCase>
            <useCase>
                <title>Health Ecosystem Data Synchronization</title>
                <primaryActor>User (Fitness Beginner)</primaryActor>
                <secondaryActors>
                    <actor>System (Integration Layer)</actor>
                </secondaryActors>
                <description>The app seamlessly synchronizes workout and health data with Apple Health and Google Fit, meeting user expectations for integrated health tracking while leveraging existing ecosystem investments.</description>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User completes a workout in the app</step>
                    <step>System automatically syncs workout data to connected health apps</step>
                    <step>User views workout in Apple Health/Google Fit dashboard</step>
                    <step>System imports steps, weight, and other metrics from health apps</step>
                    <step>Imported data is used to enhance progress tracking and recommendations</step>
                    <step>User can manage integration preferences in settings</step>
                    <step>System handles conflicts and data resolution transparently</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternativeFlows>
                    <flow id="A1" trigger="User revokes data access">
                        <step>User revokes access for specific data types in the app settings.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A2" trigger="Sync operation fails">
                        <step>Sync fails and system queues data for later retry.</step>
                    </flow>
                    <flow id="A3" trigger="User wants immediate sync">
                        <step>User manually triggers a sync operation from the settings screen.</step>
                    </flow>
                </alternativeFlows>
                <exceptionFlows/>
            </useCase>
        </useCaseModel>
    </useCases>
    <nonFunctionalRequirements>
        <requirement type="Security">All user health and personal data must be encrypted at rest and in transit, and the app must comply with GDPR and CCPA regulations to ensure user privacy and data protection.</requirement>
        <requirement type="Performance">The AI-powered nutrition analysis must return results to the user within 5 seconds for 95% of photo submissions to ensure a smooth and engaging user experience.</requirement>
    </nonFunctionalRequirements>
</productRequirementsDocument>